Panagiotis (Panos) Triantafyllidis

\(+44 7595982400 \)

takistrian@gmail.com

LinkedIn:panagiotis-triantafyllidis

Personal portfolio website: https://panostriantafyllidis.github.io/

Graduate of Business and IT currently studying MSc in Computer Science, with the target of acquiring employment in the fields of software development, security, and IT after the end of my degree. My background includes independent external study to expand my software skills, strong experience with group projects of academic and professional nature, and a military service utilised under the IT department.

Education

<u>2023-2024</u> **University of Manchester, UK – MSc Advanced Computer Science** – Currently in progress

- Undertaking the Cyber Security pathway with the following modules:
 Modelling/Querying Data on the Web , Cryptography/Cyber Security, Automated reasoning, and
 Verification/Software Security
- Working on my master's dissertation project with topic "Intrusion detection in foreign domain".

<u>2018-2022</u> **Aston University, Birmingham, UK** - BSc Business Computing and Information Technology (with placement year) – **Graduated with First Class Honours**

- Key Modules: Database Applications (79,6%), Applications Development (82%), Systems Analysis (78%), Information Security (81%), Project Delivery (76%), BCIT Research project (78%).
- Vice President of the Aston Bright Futures Society, the largest network of university societies with professional content in the UK.
- Higher Education Achievement Report provided upon request.

2017-2018 Network Foundation School, Athens, Greece

- Overall, Mark: 80% (AAB)
- Key Modules: Computing 83%, Statistics 85%, Business and Economics 85%, Project Development 80% [research and group presentation], Programming [C++, OOP, stencil] 80%
- Gained experience in presentations upon large audience, understanding the principles of group work, research and time-management, through extensive practical assignments.

2015-2018 2nd Lyceum, Argyroupolis, Athens, Greece

General Lyceum Apolyterium, GPA of graduation 'Excellent' 18.9/20.0.

Employment & Work Experience

2022-2023 Hellenic Airforce - IT and Security assistant

- Part of my military service in Greece.
- Experience includes technical support at the IT department of the Hellenic Airforce, Insight into Information Security, and tasks on Web development with HTML/CSS/JavaScript.

<u>2020-2021</u> **Skywalk Critical Services, Athens, Greece** – *Operations and IT Intern*

- Work Placement in a Supply Chain Company dealing with B2B deliveries. Assisting in daily tasks which
 included handling of 2 ERP systems (for parcel/order/vehicle management), making order
 statement/weekly reports along with insight in database maintenance and website development with
 React and HTLM/CSS/JS. Including Technical support.
- Own initiative included:
 - ✓ implementing a self-made calculator program made in Visual Basic to help with financial reportmaking and company calculations for reports and dashboard visualisation.
 - ✓ Implementing an Access database program, which makes easier and more compact, the management of information and generates excel-based Reports.

<u>2017-2018</u> "Virus" Men's wear retail store, Megara, Greece – Sales Assistant

 Part-time job, in the field of retail business. Experience gained was based on HTML, data management, marketing, and VBA/MSOffice.

Hobbies, Interests & Achievements

- I enjoy studying about Ethical hacking, including CaptureTheFlax and HackTheBox material and look for event opportunities to improve my skills in practise. Currently taking courses from the HtB.academy.com.
- Completed one semester of Web Development classes provided by the University of Athens, with focus on HTML/CSS/JS, React16, Angular and Vue.jr, with Certification. [5-month course]
- Completed online classes on in-depth Java programming, provided by the Economic University of Athens, with Certification. [4-month course 10 ECTS points]
- Bright Futures Society, Vice President, developed teamwork, communication, and time management skills through the process of conducting weekly events that connect students and employers.
- Student Course Representative, Member of the representative group of Business Computing and IT. Gave me the chance to conduct research and development for course-improvement, and propose module-specific suggestions, that directly influenced my degree experience.

Special Skills

- IT:
 - Highly Competent in MS Office used for degree assignments and projects.
 - Intermediate knowledge in Python/C++/Visual Basic/SQL/JavaScript/HTML/CSS.
 - Knowledge and understanding of Agile/Waterfall project development from the courses of Systems Analysis (learned in theory) and Applications Development (applied in practice).

Languages:

- English (IELTS Band score [7] in 2018), Studied for 5 years in England 2018-2022 and 2023-2024.
- Greek (Fluent / Mother-tongue)
- German (Beginner level /A1, A2, B1, B2)
- EU Driving Licence (GREEK): August 2018

References

Upon request